Katjvarna Empire High-Level Officer's School
First, everyone,
let me congratulate you on
successfully entering
the Katjvarna Empire Central Base's
High-Level Officer's School.
This class includes the five who rescued
Princess Chamille from the enemy
and were conferred the rank
of Imperial Knight.
Princess Chamille has also
decided to learn with you
at the young age of twelve.
I hope you find inspiration from this
to work hard at your lessons.
The Knights of the
High-Level Officer's School
Run! Keep running!
You're falling behind a lap,
Warrant Officer Ikta Solork!
Why don't you just pack up
your things and go home?
Sounds like a great idea to me—
Louder!
Sir, yes sir!
What did I do to deserve this?
Cheer up, Ikkun.
We only have crossbow practice, a lecture,
and a marathon in the afternoon!
Is that supposed to make me feel better?
And don't call me Ikkun.
Hey,
slow-ass Imperial Knight.
Uh, who are you guys?
We prepared something special
to give you energy.
Here.
Don't be shy. Eat up.
Wh-What? You wanna go?
One, two...
Thanks. Centipedes have venomous fangs,
so you need to knock the head off
or they can be dangerous.
Keep that in mind.
L-Let's go.
Using bugs against Ikta?
Talk about not knowing your enemy.
Still, that was terrible.
I couldn't handle it.
Hey, don't you think it's cute
how childish they are?
Eh, the best way to deal with
those types is to ignore them.
The smallest dogs always bark the loudest.
That sounds especially true coming from you.
Why are you talking in sync there?
Thank you for the escort.
I appreciate it.
Your words honor us.
Please focus on your studies without worry.
May I sit here, Warrant Officer Solork?
Neither the desk nor the chair belongs to me.
Do what you want, Warrant Officer Chamille.
Quiet, everyone.
This is the lecture on elementary tactics.
We will begin with chapter two,
section four, on the Japonic war.
In Imperial Year 788,
an expedition was conducted into
the far-eastern state of Japonic,
Are you enjoying your life here?
which is presently Kioka Republic territory.
It's terrible. I can't nap or
bring in lovers.
Are women all you think about?
I'm not sure what to say
about that, honestly.
What battle was notable for excellent
performance by its low-ranked officers?
Sorry. You're too young
to talk about this, huh?
Warrant Officer Chamille?
Page 132.
The Battle of A-Abhilia.
Correct.
Now, tell me why this battle
was historically significant,
Warrant Officer Solork.
The commanding officer on the
imperial side was Captain Ilshim Giorgo.
He and the 800 men in
his independent battalion
were surrounded in the wetlands of Abhilia
by three corps of Japonic soldiers,
numbering about 1600,
and were on the brink of annihilation.
Tactics at the time called for retreat,
but he had his men shed their armor,
Abhilia Wetlands
and eliminated each force in turn
before they could regroup.
Technically called "defeat in detail."
The battle is historically significant
as an example of how a tactical victory
can overcome a strategic defeat.
Very good.
But is this really correct?
His true genius
was predicting where his units and
the enemy's would be and when.
Do you understand?
In a war where decisions were based on
unit positions and relative strength,
he added a new factor: where each unit
would be at a certain point in time.
That was his real accomplishment.
Warrant Officer S-Solork!
If we really wish to learn from him,
we can't just sit here and stare at the map.
We must picture the units
moving in real time,
as if we're playing blindfolded chess.
That's all.
The Next Day
I hate to say it,
but with your skills, you could probably
snipe an enemy commander.
Thanks, Ma-kun.
Being able to shoot a distant enemy
is a huge advantage,
so I want to master that skill first.
That's a big goal.
Is that you, Toruru?
Look, Sushura. The Imperial Knight is here.
It's been a long time, Toruru.
We just got back from the
Northern Garrison fortress.
You a friend of his?
I'm Sarihaslag Remeon.
His brother.
And the big guy is Sushuraf Remeon.
And you are?
Warrant Officer M-Matthew Tetdrich.
One of the five who saved
the Third Princess, right?
Well, as his brother, I should thank you.
He slowed you down, didn't he?
My little brother, I mean.
No, Torway actually...
You don't need to defend him
when he doesn't deserve it.
While he's good at shooting from afar,
that's because he doesn't
want to be near the enemy.
He's a huge coward.
Right, Toruru?
So, Matthew-kun,
as soon as things start to
look even a little bad,
he'll abandon his comrades and run—
I won't run!
Hey, Toruru,
who said you could interrupt me?
I-I...
You what?!
Come out and say it!
"I feel sick just looking at your face."
"I wish it would explode."
It is written in the scriptures
of the Aledelans...
"No mercy for sadistic, hot assholes."
Don't worry.
I took off the head.
I-Ikkun...
Stop calling me that.
Who are you?
A friend of Toruru?
Some pretty boys I can handle,
and some I can't.
You're in the latter camp.
Appearance court declares you guilty.
You are sentenced to explode, immediately.
Ikta!
Just like I said!
His friend's being hit right in front of him,
but he's too scared to stop me!
Not only are you an asshole sadist,
you're stupid, too?
If you were the commander
in a war of attrition,
you'd fall for the enemy's provocations
and be wiped out!
You're still running your mouth?!
Sure am.
A barbarian punches someone
when he feels like it,
a soldier attacks when it's time to attack,
and Ikta Solork says everything he wants
whenever he wants to say it.
You asshole!
Your turn.
I don't know what's going on, but all right.
I see interaction between soldiers
is a very violent thing, Yatori.
P-Princess Chamille...
Yes.
I believe Ikta asked the upperclassmen
to spar with him.
Ikta, what are the rules?
Five versus one, and you're allowed
to attack after they're down, I guess.
Roger.
Since he's been knocked down,
I, Yatorishino Igsem,
shall take his place.
Let us resume.
U-Uh, hang on—
Don't screw with us—
Now...
Who's next?
Don't get cocky.
Don't, Sushura.
Stop it.
That's enough sparring.
Princess, we'll be leaving.
Don't think this is the end.
Mil, make some ice.
My stomach hurts...
My back hurts...
Don't worry.
Ikta's a lot tougher than he looks.
But...
It's my fault my brothers...
Where'd you get that idea, hottie?
A sadistic hottie interrupted my nap,
so I got him back, is all.
You're crazy.
I know that was planned, Solork.
You started that fight knowing that
Yatori and I were coming.
Hey, Haro.
Can you give this princess,
who wants to show off her insight,
some advice from an elder?
Let's see...
Some things are better left unsaid?
I'm sorry!
Hey, Torway.
Do you know why you fight a war of attrition?
Y-Yeah.
You want to avoid a decisive battle,
buy time, and wait for another chance, right?
If you understand, then fine.
But, well, that's the most difficult thing.
Three Months Later
Listen up.
You will now each be given
a platoon of imperial soldiers!
This is a big responsibility, so own it!
Sir, yes sir!
Warrant Officer Yatorishino Igsem.
Fire Troop Platoon 1!
It is an honor, sir.
Warrant Officer Torway Remeon,
Air Rifle Platoon 1.
It is an honor, sir.
Warrant Officer Ikta Solork.
Light Troop Platoon 3.
It's an honor, sir.
Congratulations on assuming command of
the platoon, Warrant Officer Solork.
We're glad to have you here.
Thanks. You, too.
What's your name, Sergeant Major?
I believe you already know my name.
What? Have we met before?
Sergeant Major Suya Mitcalif.
You were on intimate terms
with my mother two years ago.
Are you Amishia's...
Yes. Her daughter.
But, Warrant Officer,
please never say her name again.
You adulterer.
The daughter of a woman
you were sleeping with?!
I can't say I approve of breaking
a married woman's vows.
I was told she was divorced.
Anyway, the whole platoon knows about it.
Nobody's going to listen to me.
Suya's not even letting me lead.
Solve that problem yourself.
I haven't the slightest bit of sympathy.
Fine.
I won't ask for your help anymore.
Please remain seated, Your Highness.
You too, Torway.
But Yatori...
He's done so much for me...
His own carelessness brought this on.
It just means there's no need to worry.
If that was enough to stop him,
Ikta Solork wouldn't be here
in the first place.
Stop.
All troops, left.
They're pretty well-trained.
Look at that.
His troops are ignoring him.
We need to show him his place.
Th-They got us!
This is bad! Ultra bad!
What's bad?
The mock battle!
They put up the details for it!
Six platoons will split into two
and fight with paint rounds, right?
The problem's how they split it!
One side is me, Ikta, and Torway,
and the other is Yatori, Captain Sarihaslag,
and Lieutenant Sushura!
So, graduated officers are
coming back to bully us, huh?
I'm surprised they liked me so much.
Is now really the time to be so relaxed?
I-I'm sorry. It's my fault.
Don't get so cocky, hottie.
I'm obviously the main target
for their revenge.
Honestly, Matthew's just an afterthought.
I agree.
I feel bad for him.
Seriously, why do you two only agree
when it's time to pick on me?
What about Haro's medic squad?
I think we'll be treating
the wounded from both sides
rather than participating in the battle.
Now's not the time to worry
about other people!
Now, calm down, Matthew.
This is just an exercise.
We've been in a real experience
where we risked our lives, right?
Anyway, I'm off to go turn
danger into opportunity.
So, what do you want?
I don't need your input for
the next training exercise.
You're not even giving me a chance, huh?
Is it because I slept with your mom?
No...
I see.
So you're not disrupting the chain of
command over a personal grudge.
Then why is it?
It's because...
Your physical aptitude is below standards.
And I can't see you as fit
for command on the ground.
Is that the reason?
Th-That's right.
If you're so good at desk work,
you should do that instead of command.
I see.
By the way, Suya, you heard
about the mock battle, right?
You think you can win that?
I hate to say it,
but probably not.
They're much more skilled than us.
In that case, if I lead us to victory,
that means I'm a better
commander than you, right?
Why do you...
Because I'd be doing something you couldn't.
So, at least, it'd prove I'm not
an incompetent commander.
Fine.
If we win the mock battle,
and you play a major role in the victory...
You'll let me command the platoon?
But what if you lose?
Then I'll go take a desk job, like you say.
Does that work?
Fine.
Southern Urt Forests
This weather's a real problem.
It's ruining our attempts to tell
ourselves we're off to a fun picnic.
I'm sorry, Warrant Officer Remeon,
but why is our commander... um...
that man?
Because he's the most suited for it.
The target is 30 kilometers to the south.
We'll sleep outside tonight
and arrive tomorrow afternoon.
No, we're setting up camp
at the site by nightfall.
Listen, Warrant Officer,
30 kilometers is as the crows flies.
You need to think—
Yeah.
Of course I thought about it.
Anyway, can you not scream too much?
You're scaring the troops.
No need to hurry, guys.
It's easy to get lost on
their complicated route.
This'll be easy.
It seems Captain Sarihaslag
knows this training ground well.
What will Solork do?
It's always hard to guess what Ikta will do.
Even after knowing him this long?
He takes into account what
you think he's going to do, too.
By the way, Your Highness,
please make sure you're not
caught up in the crossfire.
Stay behind them at all times.
I'm aware.
Everyone, you took out what I told
you to from your luggage, right?
Okay, all troops, move to the left.
All right!
Back to march!
Warrant Officer, it's against
orders to throw away our baggage.
I'm not throwing them away.
This is a supply depot.
What if we need them at the battle?
I chose what we left carefully.
We can dilute the paint for the bullets
with water to get more of it,
and with the tent exteriors
we can escape the weather.
But the higher-ups determined the list—
How the baggage is used is within
the ground command's discretion.
That's why we made a depot!
Exercise Day 1
Okay, call roll.
We really made it before sunset...
Have you been here before?
Nope, it's my first time.
You're lying!
You didn't use a map once on
the way here, Warrant Officer!
It's a pain to keep taking the
map out when it's raining.
On the other hand, the map in here
doesn't get wet and takes no time at all.
The rest is... experience, maybe?
My master trained me
from when I was young.
Fieldwork is the most
basic element of science.
Science?
I'll go take a look at the Kuriri River
to the south later.
Tomorrow, we'll make camp beyond.
Wha—
Please wait!
The orders said the north plains
were where we are to—
They said it was an ideal place
for our forces to meet, is all.
I can interpret that to mean
I'm allowed to make camp
anywhere in the forest I like.
If I've got the choice,
I want a battlefield that
works to my advantage.
Exercise Day 2
It's almost noon and there's no sign of them.
Will they make it by sunset?
Captain Sarihaslag.
My scouts have returned.
The enemy is camped on the other side
of the Kuriri River, to the south.
What?!
We're supposed to fight here!
All the orders said was that this
would be an ideal place to meet.
I would not interpret that as
orders on where we fight.
A-All forces, advance to the south!
Hurry!
Well, then.
Yatori should have noticed by now.
The sadistic hottie will start
to panic and head down here,
since he won't want to be incompetently late.
Matthew, Torway, you're ready, right?
Yeah.
Yes.
Imperial Year 906, June.
It's said that this mock battle
is the first time Ikta Solork
showed a glimpse of his genius.
Next time: Watchdogs of the Spirit Tree.
Watchdogs of the Spirit Tree